<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Croissants :: Recipe Book</title>
    <link>https://bpms-hub.github.io/recipe-book/pastry/croissant/index.html</link>
    <description>Ingredients Ingredient ½ Batch 1 Batch Bread Flour 500g 1000g Whole Milk 140g 280g Water 110g 220g Sugar 50g 100g Salt 10g 20g Instant Yeast 7g 14g Butter (dough) 50g 100g Butter (lamination) 250g 500g Dough Preparation Combine flour, milk, water, sugar, salt, yeast, and dough butter in a mixer. Mix on low speed until a smooth, slightly tacky dough forms (about 3–5 minutes). Do not overmix; gluten should be developed but not tight. Wrap dough and refrigerate for at least 4 hours or overnight. Lamination (RAM Sheeter) Prepare Butter Block: Shape lamination butter into a flat, even rectangle (about 1cm thick). Chill until firm but pliable. Lock-In: Roll dough into a rectangle twice the size of the butter block. Place butter on one half, fold dough over, and seal edges. First Roll: Using the RAM sheeter, roll dough to 7mm thickness. Perform a single (letter) fold. Rest: Wrap and refrigerate for 30–45 minutes. Second Roll: Roll to 7mm again, perform another single fold. Rest as above. Third Roll: Roll to 7mm, perform a final single fold. Rest at least 1 hour before shaping. Shaping Roll laminated dough to 4mm thickness using the RAM sheeter. Trim edges for clean layers. Cut triangles (base about 8cm, height about 20cm). Gently stretch each triangle, then roll up from base to tip, keeping tension but not compressing layers. Place croissants on parchment-lined trays, tip side down. Proofing &amp; Refrigeration Proof at 24–26°C (75–78°F), 75–80% humidity, until doubled and very jiggly (about 2–3 hours). For best flavor and convenience, you can retard shaped croissants in the fridge overnight after partial proof (about 1 hour at room temp, then refrigerate). Baking Preheat oven to 400°F (205°C) with convection, or 425°F (220°C) without. Brush croissants with egg wash (1 egg + pinch of salt). Bake for 16–20 minutes, rotating halfway, until deep golden brown and crisp. Cool on rack before serving. Tips:</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bpms-hub.github.io/recipe-book/pastry/croissant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>