<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Breads :: Recipe Book</title>
    <link>https://bpms-hub.github.io/recipe-book/breads/index.html</link>
    <description>Here you’ll find recipes for all our classic and specialty breads, including enriched, sourdough, and whole grain varieties. Updates 2025-06-04: Added Whole Wheat Bread recipe with improved hydration and shaping tips. 2025-06-03: Rye Bread recipe now includes new fermentation schedule. 2025-06-02: Sourdough recipe updated with starter maintenance instructions. 2025-06-01: Breads section launched with Brioche, Rye, Sourdough, and Whole Wheat recipes. Recipes Brioche Rye Sourdough Whole Wheat</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bpms-hub.github.io/recipe-book/breads/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brioche</title>
      <link>https://bpms-hub.github.io/recipe-book/breads/brioche/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bpms-hub.github.io/recipe-book/breads/brioche/index.html</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Ingredient ½ Batch 1 Batch Bread Flour 250g 500g Eggs 110g 220g Whole Milk 30g 60g Sugar 35g 70g Salt 5g 10g Instant Yeast 5g 10g Unsalted Butter (soft) 125g 250g Mixing In a stand mixer bowl, combine flour, sugar, salt, and yeast. Add eggs and milk. Mix on low speed until a shaggy dough forms. Increase speed to medium and knead until dough is smooth and elastic (about 8–10 minutes). Gradually add the softened butter in small pieces, mixing until fully incorporated and dough is shiny and smooth. Cover bowl and let dough rise at room temperature until doubled (about 1–2 hours). Punch down dough, cover, and refrigerate overnight (or at least 4 hours) for easier shaping. Shaping Turn chilled dough onto a lightly floured surface. For a classic loaf: Divide dough as needed, shape into a log, and place in a greased loaf pan. For individual brioche à tête: Divide into small balls, place in greased brioche molds, and pinch a small piece off each to form the “head.” Cover and let rise until doubled and puffy (about 1–2 hours at room temperature). Baking Preheat oven to 350°F (175°C). Brush tops with egg wash (1 egg beaten with a splash of milk). Bake loaves for 30–35 minutes, or small brioche for 18–22 minutes, until deep golden brown and hollow-sounding when tapped. Cool in pan for 10 minutes, then unmold and cool completely on a rack before slicing or packaging.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rye</title>
      <link>https://bpms-hub.github.io/recipe-book/breads/rye/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bpms-hub.github.io/recipe-book/breads/rye/index.html</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Ingredient ½ Batch 1 Batch Bread Flour 200g 400g Rye Flour 150g 300g Water 200g 400g Sourdough Starter (100% hydration) 75g 150g Salt 7g 14g Caraway Seeds (opt.) 3g 6g Molasses (opt.) 10g 20g Instant Yeast (if not using only starter) 2g 4g Mixing In a large bowl, combine bread flour, rye flour, and salt. Add water, sourdough starter, and molasses (if using). Mix until a sticky dough forms. Knead by hand or with a mixer until dough is elastic and slightly tacky (about 5–7 minutes). Mix in caraway seeds if desired. Cover and let rise at room temperature until doubled (about 2–3 hours, or overnight in the fridge for more flavor). Shaping Turn dough onto a lightly floured surface. Shape into a round or oblong loaf, or place in a greased loaf pan. Cover and let rise until puffy and nearly doubled (about 1 hour). Baking Preheat oven to 425°F (220°C). Place a pan of water in the oven for steam. Score the top of the loaf with a sharp blade. Bake for 30–35 minutes, until deep brown and hollow-sounding when tapped. Cool completely on a rack before slicing or packaging.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough</title>
      <link>https://bpms-hub.github.io/recipe-book/breads/sourdough/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bpms-hub.github.io/recipe-book/breads/sourdough/index.html</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Ingredient ½ Batch 1 Batch Bread Flour 250g 500g Whole Wheat Flour 50g 100g Water 200g 400g Sourdough Starter (100% hydration) 50g 100g Salt 6g 12g Mixing In a large bowl, combine bread flour, whole wheat flour, and water. Mix until just combined. Cover and let rest (autolyse) for 30–45 minutes. Add sourdough starter and salt. Mix by hand until fully incorporated. Perform a series of stretch and folds every 30 minutes for 2 hours, keeping the dough covered between folds. Bulk Fermentation Let dough rise at room temperature (21–24°C/70–75°F) until nearly doubled, about 4–5 hours total (including folding time). Shaping Turn dough onto a lightly floured surface. Pre-shape into a round, cover, and rest 20 minutes. Shape into a tight round or oval loaf. Place seam-side up in a floured proofing basket. Final Proof Cover and proof at room temperature for 1–2 hours, or refrigerate overnight for improved flavor and scoring. Baking Preheat oven to 500°F (260°C) with a Dutch oven or baking stone inside. Turn loaf onto parchment, score the top with a sharp blade. Transfer to the hot Dutch oven, cover, and bake 20 minutes with lid on. Remove lid, reduce temperature to 450°F (230°C), and bake 20–25 minutes more until deep golden brown. Cool completely on a rack before slicing or packaging.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whole Wheat</title>
      <link>https://bpms-hub.github.io/recipe-book/breads/whole-wheat/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bpms-hub.github.io/recipe-book/breads/whole-wheat/index.html</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Ingredient ½ Batch 1 Batch Whole Wheat Flour 250g 500g Bread Flour 100g 200g Water 230g 460g Honey (or sugar) 20g 40g Olive Oil (or butter) 15g 30g Salt 7g 14g Instant Yeast 4g 8g Mixing In a large bowl, combine whole wheat flour, bread flour, salt, and yeast. Add water, honey, and olive oil. Mix until a shaggy dough forms. Knead by hand or with a mixer until smooth and elastic (about 8–10 minutes). Dough will be slightly tacky. Bulk Fermentation Cover and let rise at room temperature until doubled in size, about 1–1.5 hours. Shaping Turn dough onto a lightly floured surface. Shape into a loaf or rolls as desired. Place in a greased loaf pan or on a baking sheet. Cover and let rise until puffy and nearly doubled, about 45–60 minutes. Baking Preheat oven to 375°F (190°C). Bake loaf for 30–35 minutes, or rolls for 18–22 minutes, until golden brown and hollow-sounding when tapped. Cool on a rack before slicing or packaging.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>